<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on OHBM DIC</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on OHBM DIC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Organization for Human Brain Mapping - Diversity and Inclusivity Committee. All rights reserved. | Contact OHBM-DIC</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ohbm-dic.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Affinity Groups</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/affinitygroups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/affinitygroups/</guid><description>How can we achieve a balance of speakers at a scientific event? Finding speakers outside one’s network can be accomplished by contacting affinity groups that are organized around specific identities to seek eligible individuals with the relevant expertise on a given topic. This will entail including speakers from underrepresented backgrounds and geographical locations as well as considering gender, ethnicity, and career levels when choosing co-presenters.
We compiled a list of affinity groups https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/codeofconduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/codeofconduct/</guid><description>The OHBM Code of Conduct is outlined at
https://www.humanbrainmapping.org/i4a/pages/index.cfm?pageid=3912</description></item><item><title>DIC Symposium: 2021</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/symposia/2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/symposia/2021/</guid><description>Take a look what who joined the OHBM 2021 DIC symposium and what we discussed!
https://www.ohbmbrainmappingblog.com/blog/what-to-expect-from-the-diversity-and-inclusivity-committee-at-the-2021-ohbm-annual-meeting</description></item><item><title>DIC Symposium: 2022</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/symposia/2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/symposia/2022/</guid><description>Check out our annual DIC symposium at OHBM 2022!
https://www.ohbmbrainmappingblog.com/blog/diversity-inclusivity-events-at-the-2022-ohbm-annual-meeting-if-you-want-to-go-far-go-together</description></item><item><title>DIC Symposium: 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/symposia/2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/symposia/2023/</guid><description>Using technology to enhance diversity and inclusivity in neuroscience and neuroimaging Organizers: Lucina Q. Uddin, Rosanna Olsen, Kangjoo Lee and OHBM Diversity and Inclusivity Committee
Timeliness, importance of topic and desired learning outcomes: OHBM initially launched a Diversity and Gender Task Force in 2017 to address the growing need to recognize and address multiple forms of inequity with respect to gender balance and geographical representation on the Council. Since 2017, this initiative has worked towards tackling a range of issues surrounding underrepresentation at OHBM.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2021</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2021/</guid><description>Watch on youtube at https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLocwiMktiT-6qUcqfP1qronR16EHLW3NM</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2022</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2022/</guid><description>Watch on youtube at https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLocwiMktiT-5w99sH6XGSWwsMyj2TMlm_</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/</guid><description>The Diversity and Inclusivity Committee (DIC) at OHBM organizes the annual Multilingual Kids Live Review events in 2023 (FREE events). This year, we host 18 1-hour sessions in 12 different languages to connect the scientists from today at OHBM to children (8-15 years old) all over the world. The main objective of these presentations is to have children learn about your scientific work and get them excited about science and the brain.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2023 - Event Registration</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/registration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/registration/</guid><description>No registration fee. Event information can be found in : https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/ Currently registrations are open for the sessions: French I, French II, Greek, Italian I, Italian II, Italian III, Japanese, Korean, Mandarin I, Mandarin II, Portuguese, Spanish and Traditional Chinese (Taiwan) The following sessions are in preparation and the corresponding webpages are under construction: Bengali, English, German I, German II, Marathi Bengali [In preparation] https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeTPJIjjuPtcWM7Z9CTDNADjKeF35I4BAUNPrvGl5qAor-tow/viewform?usp=sf_link
English [In preparation] https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Bengali 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/bengali_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/bengali_session/</guid><description> Currently registrations are open for the sessions: French I, French II, Greek, Italian I, Italian II, Italian III, Japanese, Korean, Mandarin I, Mandarin II, Portuguese, Spanish and Traditional Chinese (Taiwan) The following sessions are in preparation and the corresponding webpages are under construction: Bengali, English, German I, German II, Marathi</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: English 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/english_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/english_session/</guid><description> Currently registrations are open for the sessions: French I, French II, Greek, Italian I, Italian II, Italian III, Japanese, Korean, Mandarin I, Mandarin II, Portuguese, Spanish and Traditional Chinese (Taiwan) The following sessions are in preparation and the corresponding webpages are under construction: Bengali, English, German I, German II, Marathi</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: French 2023 - Est-ce que l'antioxydant glutathion varie avec l'âge, et comment ?</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/french/french/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/french/french/</guid><description>Vous êtes-vous déjà demandé ce qui se passe dans votre cerveau et dans le reste de votre corps lorsque vous vieillissez ? Quelles sont les réactions chimiques nocives qui se produisent dans votre corps avec l&amp;rsquo;âge ? Est-il possible de mesurer ces changements chimiques dans le cerveau et le sang ?
Si vous souhaitez en savoir plus sur la façon dont le cerveau et le reste de votre corps se protègent contre ces réactions chimiques nocives grâce à des composés chimiques super-héros appelés antioxydants, venez à notre session « Est-ce que l&amp;rsquo;antioxydant glutathion varie avec l&amp;rsquo;âge, et comment ?</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: French 2023 - Les commotions cérébrales!</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/french/french_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/french/french_2/</guid><description>Nos cerveaux sont des organes incroyablement impressionnants qui nous permettent de faire ce que nous faisons et d&amp;rsquo;être qui nous sommes! Mais comment fonctionnent-ils et que se passe-t-il lorsqu&amp;rsquo;ils sont blessés? Franchissez la dernière frontière du corps et découvrez le cerveau avec nous! Nous explorerons le fonctionnement du cerveau et ce qui se passe lorsque vous avez une commotion cérébrale, à travers une présentation, une discussion et quelques activités!
Date et l&amp;rsquo;heure: samedi 20 mai 2023, 13h</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: German 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/german/german/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/german/german/</guid><description> Currently registrations are open for the sessions: French I, French II, Greek, Italian I, Italian II, Italian III, Japanese, Korean, Mandarin I, Mandarin II, Portuguese, Spanish and Traditional Chinese (Taiwan) The following sessions are in preparation and the corresponding webpages are under construction: Bengali, English, German I, German II, Marathi</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: German 2023 [2] - title</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/german/german_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/german/german_2/</guid><description> Currently registrations are open for the sessions: French I, French II, Greek, Italian I, Italian II, Italian III, Japanese, Korean, Mandarin I, Mandarin II, Portuguese, Spanish and Traditional Chinese (Taiwan) The following sessions are in preparation and the corresponding webpages are under construction: Bengali, English, German I, German II, Marathi</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Greek 2023 - Φαντάσματα στο υπνοδωμάτιο: βλέποντας πράγματα που δεν είναι εκεί</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/greek_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/greek_session/</guid><description>Έχεις μπει ποτέ στο σκοτεινό υπνοδωμάτιο σου με το φόβο ενός φαντάσματος στις σκιές; Σίγουρα ανακουφίζεσαι όταν ανάβεις τα φώτα και βρίσκεις μια στοίβα με ρούχα στην καρέκλα σου! Ασθενείς με άνοια ή Πάρκινσον κάνουν τέτοια λάθη αρκετά συχνά. Γιατί ο εγκέφαλος να σκαρφίζεται τρομακτικές εξηγήσεις όταν δεν είναι σίγουρος; Γιατί μερικές φορές να σκαρφίζεται πράγματα που δεν είναι εκεί</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Italian 2023 - Quante lingue parli? Lo dice il tuo cervello!</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/italian/italian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/italian/italian/</guid><description>Benvenuti nella nostra pagina!
Siamo felici che abbiate scelto di partecipare al nostro evento sulla comunicazione scientifica e non vediamo l’ora di incontrarvi. Siamo Alessandra e Giulia, due ricercatrici che lavorano in Svizzera e in Canada. Ci siamo incontrate nel 2021 all’edizione online di questo evento e abbiamo deciso di proporre quest’anno una attività di persona, per cercare di ristabilire un po’ di normalità. Grazie alla tecnologia, però, abbiamo la possibilità di lavorare insieme nonostante ci troviamo ai due capi opposti dell’Oceano Atlantico.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Japanese 2023 - 知りたい？脳の中の高速道路</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/japanese_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/japanese_session/</guid><description>このイベントでは、８歳から14歳ぐらいの子供たちを対象に、脳（のう）の研究についての紹介を研究者が日本語で行います。今年のイベントでは、MRI（えむあーるあい）という機械を使った脳の研究の紹介を竹村　浩昌（たけむら　ひろまさ）先生が行います。脳の中には、遠く離れた場所どうしをつないでいる高速道路のような線維（せんい）の束があります。今回、MRIを使って生きているヒトの脳から線維の束を見る方法やこの高速道路がどんなふうに使われているのかを皆さんにご紹介します！竹村先生からのお話の後に、皆さんからの質問コーナーも用意しています。脳の中の高速道路のはたらきや、脳について知りたいな、と思っていることについて、一緒にお話しましょう！</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Korean (한국어) 2023 - 우리는 왜 친구들과 사이좋게 지내야 할까요?</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/korean_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/korean_session/</guid><description>오랜 시간 다른 사람들과 함께하지 못하고 혼자서 생활하는 것이 우리의 머리와 마음에 어떤 영향을 줄까요? 사람과 같이 사회적 동물인 쥐를 이용한 실험을 통해 이 질문에 대해 알아보았어요. 실험 결과, 혼자 오래 생활한 쥐들은 긴장을 많이 하고 공격적인 행동을 하면서, 다른 쥐들과 같이 있지 않으려고 했어요. 그리고 행동뿐만 아니라 쥐의 머릿속 뇌에서도 커다란 변화를 관찰할 수 있었어요. 그럼 이렇게 혼자 생활한 쥐들이 다시 다른 쥐들과 함께 생활하게 되면 다시 성격이 돌아올까요? 뇌도 다시 변할까요?</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Mandarin 2023 - 绘制从儿童到老年大脑结构的变化</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/mandarin/mandarin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/mandarin/mandarin/</guid><description>大脑作为人体中很重要且复杂的器官，它的结构会随着年龄的增长而发生变化。大脑结构对我们的思考和行为方式有重大影响，因此了解我们的大脑结构如何随着年龄的增长而变化非常重要。在本次报告中，我将向我们的年轻听众解释我们如何使用磁共振成像技术拍摄我们活体大脑的“照片”，我并将向他们介绍我们研究小组绘制的从儿童到老年的人类大脑结构变化图。</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Marathi 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/marathi_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/marathi_session/</guid><description> Currently registrations are open for the sessions: French I, French II, Greek, Italian I, Italian II, Italian III, Japanese, Korean, Mandarin II, Portuguese, Spanish and Traditional Chinese (Taiwan) The following sessions are in preparation and the corresponding webpages are under construction: Bengali, English, German I, German II, Mandarin I, Marathi</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Portguese (Português) 2023 - O Cérebro e Nossos Movimentos</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/portuguese_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/portuguese_session/</guid><description>Quer ensinar mais sobre o cérebro e o corpo humano para seus filhos(as) ou alunos(as)?
Estaremos online e ao vivo para apresentar especialmente para crianças entre 8 e 15 anos de idade sobre como o cérebro funciona e como ele controla nossos movimentos. As crianças terão a oportunidade de conversar com experientes pesquisadores sobre ciência e o cérebro!
Convidamos professores e diretores de escola a inscreverem suas turmas de alunos, e pais e mães para inscreverem seus filhos.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Spanish 2023 - ¿Cómo la comida afecta a nuestro cerebro?</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/spanish_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/spanish_session/</guid><description>La comida es nuestra fuente de energía, gracias a ella podemos hacer muchas actividades en el día, como estudiar, ver la tele o jugar, pero ¿cómo la comida se convierte en energía? y ¿cómo funciona nuestro cerebro según lo que comamos? Los científicos se están encargando de describir qué pasa en nuestro cerebro. Ahora sabemos que nuestro cerebro puede estar saludable o tener malos momentos por lo que comemos, esto podría afectar nuestros pensamientos o incluso si ponemos atención en clase.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Traditional Chinese (Taiwan) 2023 - 跟著我們探索思覺失調症，解密變幻莫測的大腦活動！</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/traditionalchinese_taiwan_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/traditionalchinese_taiwan_session/</guid><description>你知道我們的大腦是宇宙中最複雜的東西之一嗎？它像是超級電腦一樣運作，由許多零件組成，當我們思考或學習時，所有零件和諧地運作著。但是，精神疾病就好像大腦中某些零件遵循了不同的規律，使得大腦難以正常運作。在這次的演講中，我們將介紹科學家們如何使用功能性磁共振成像(fMRI)研究大腦，揭開思覺失調症大腦的複雜性。透過了解大腦如何運作，可以為精神疾患開發新的治療方法，並幫助患者更健康地生活##</description></item><item><title>OHBM DIC: Our Mission</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/ourmission/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/ourmission/</guid><description>DIVERSITY AND INCLUSIVITY COMMITTEE CHARGE A critical part of the Organization for Human Brain Mapping’s strategic initiatives is to develop a plan that will ensure that gender, cultural, and geographic diversity exists within OHBM’s activities and, in particular, the Annual Meeting. This plan should further advance the Organization’s enduring mission to create a wholly diverse, engaged, and inclusive international community of those dedicated to discover the organization of the human brain.</description></item><item><title>Our team</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/ourteam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/ourteam/</guid><description>2022-2023 Diversity and Inclusivity Committee Lucina Uddin, United States - Chair Kangjoo Lee, United States - Chair-elect and Open Science SIG Liaison Rosanna Olsen, Canada - Past Chair Athina Tzovara, Switzerland - Ad-Hoc Member Julio Alejandro Yanes, United States - Ad-Hoc Member Laura Marzetti, Italy - Ad-Hoc Member Pradeep Reddy Raamana, United States - Ad-Hoc Member Tan Davynn, Singapore - Ad-Hoc Member Tilak Ratnanather, United States - Ad-Hoc Member Alexander Barnett, Canada - Ad-Hoc Member Maryam Ziaei, Norway (Australia) - Ad-Hoc Member Julia Kam, Canada - Ad-Hoc Member Sharna Jamader, Australia - Ad-Hoc Member Isaac Khobo, South Africa - Ad-Hoc Member Fernanda Hansen Pacheco de Moraes, Brazil - Ad-Hoc Member Christienne Gonzales Damatac, Netherlands - Ad-Hoc Member Jessica Damoiseaux, United States - Council Liaison Beverly Setzer, United States - Student and Postdoc SIG Liaison Lena Oestreich Australia - Brain Art SIG Liaison Eduardo Garza-Villarreal, Mexico - Communications Committee Liaison</description></item><item><title>Past Members</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/pastmembers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/about_us/pastmembers/</guid><description>2021-2022 Rosanna Olsen, Canada Chair Lucina Uddin, United States Chair-Elect AmanPreet Badhwar, Canada Past Chair Athina Tzovara, Switzerland Former Past Chair Julio Alejandro Yanes, United States Ad Hoc Member Laura Marzetti, Italy Ad Hoc Member Pradeep Reddy Raamana, United States Ad Hoc Member Tan Davynn, Sri Lanka Ad Hoc Member Tilak Ratnanather, Singapore Ad Hoc Member Lee Jollans, Germany Ad Hoc Member Alexander Barnett, Canada Ad Hoc Member Kangjoo Lee, United States Ad Hoc Member Maryam Ziaei, Australia Ad Hoc Member Julia Kam, Canada Ad Hoc Member Svenja Caspers, Germany Council Liaison Anne Billot, United States SPSIG Liaison Stephanie Noble, United States OSSIG Liaison Valentina Borghesani, United States Brain Art SIG Liaison Kevin Sitek, United States ComCom Liaison 2020-2021 AmanPreet Badhwar, Canada Chair Rosanna Olsen, Canada Chair Elect Athina Tzovara, Switzerland Past Chair Gina Rippon, United Kingdom Ad Hoc Member Hyang Woon Lee, Korea Ad Hoc Member Julio Alejandro Yanes, United States Ad Hoc Member Laura Marzetti, Italy Ad Hoc Member Pradeep Reddy Raamana, Canada Ad Hoc Member Tan Davynn, Sri Lanka Ad Hoc Member Tilak Ratnanather, Singapore Ad Hoc Member Lucina Uddin, United States Ad Hoc Member Lee Jollans, Germany Ad Hoc Member Sharlene Newman, United States Awards Committee Liaison Helen Zhou, Singapore Council Liaison Hajer Nakua, Canada SPSIG Liaison Melvin Selim Atay, Turkey OSSIG Liaison Valentina Borghesani, United States Brain Art SIG Liaison Nils Muhlert, United Kingdom ComCom Liaison 2019-2020 Athina Tzovara, Switzerland Chair AmanPreet Badhwar Chair-Elect Ishmael Amarreh, United States Past Chair Rosanna Olsen, Canada Ad Hoc Member Gina Rippon, United Kingdom Ad Hoc Member Hyang Woon Lee, Korea Ad Hoc Member Maria Luisa Bringas Vega, China/Cuba Ad Hoc Member Mallar M.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Italian 2023 - Cos’è la memoria? E come la usiamo per imparare una nuova lingua</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/italian/italian_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/italian/italian_2/</guid><description>Ciao!
Ci chiamiamo Irene e Isotta e siamo due neuroscienziate che studiano il funzionamento del cervello all’Università di Ginevra.
Isotta lavora sulla connettività cerebrale e sull&amp;rsquo;epilessia, una malattia caratterizzata da un&amp;rsquo;attivazione inaspettata in tutto il cervello (crisi epilettica). Pur lavorando per l&amp;rsquo;Università, la sua sede è l&amp;rsquo;ospedale, dove studia l&amp;rsquo;attività cerebrale dei pazienti per capire se è possibile trovare segni della malattia anche quando il cervello funziona in modo normale. Le crisi epilettiche spesso iniziano nell&amp;rsquo;ippocampo, una parte del cervello fondamentale per la memoria.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Mandarin 2023 - 构筑彩巢、探密青春、关爱脑智</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/mandarin/mandarin2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/mandarin/mandarin2/</guid><description>Theme: Building Color Nests, Probing Youth, Caring Brain &amp;amp; Mind 我们每个人都头顶一个独一无二的大脑。在讲座中，我将带领大家通过一个在中国家喻户晓的传统神话人物，脚踏风火轮，手拿金刚戟的“莲花童子”—哪吒。通过他的成长故事，与大家一起分享脑智发育的科学规律，介绍我们中国人的彩巢计划，带你一起探秘青春成长的烦恼，呼吁我们家庭、社会和学校来共同关爱儿童脑智健康, 关心他们未来的一生成长。
Every brain matters. In this talk, you will get to know a household legendary character from traditional Chinese myth, Ne Zha, also known as “Lotus Prince”, whose growing up story will give you a glimpse into the fascinating development of brain and mind. Over the past decade, our research team have devoted to collecting data on brain and mind across different stages of the human lifespan (6-85 years old) in China.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Italian 2023 - Leggere la mente usando le interazioni cerebrali funzionali</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/italian/italian_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/italian/italian_3/</guid><description>Ciao,
siamo Antea, Laura e Roberto e facciamo parte del MAMBO, un gruppo di ricerca dell’Università di Chieti che studia il funzionamento del cervello. In particolare stiamo studiando come i neuroni parlano tra di loro e di come queste comunicazioni, chiamate in gergo, connettività funzionale, sono utilizzate per qualsiasi compito dalla decisione alla memoria.
Antea è una psicologa-psicoterapeuta e all’interno del gruppo MAMBO studia come diverse aree del cervello comunicano tra di loro per svolgere diversi compiti della nostra vita quotidiana!</description></item><item><title>Best practices for ensuring diversity of presenters at OHBM</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/fourth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/fourth/</guid><description>Check out our OHBM blog post about &amp;ldquo;Best practices for ensuring diversity of presenters at OHBM&amp;rdquo; published in December 1, 2022!
https://www.ohbmbrainmappingblog.com/blog/best-practices-for-ensuring-diversity-of-presenters-at-ohbm</description></item><item><title>Diversity and Inclusivity Events at the 2022 OHBM Annual Meeting</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/third/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/third/</guid><description>Check out our latest OHBM post that reviews the events hosted by OHBM DIC in the annual meeting of OHBM published in May 27, 2022!
https://www.ohbmbrainmappingblog.com/blog/diversity-inclusivity-events-at-the-2022-ohbm-annual-meeting-if-you-want-to-go-far-go-together</description></item><item><title>Results from the Survey on Inclusivity at OHBM - Summary and Future Directions</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/second/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/second/</guid><description>We collected and analyzed the results from our survey on inclusivity at OHBM. Check out our summary and suggested future directions.
https://www.ohbmbrainmappingblog.com/blog/results-from-the-survey-on-inclusivity-at-ohbm-summary-and-future-directions</description></item><item><title>What to expect from the DIC at the 2021 OHBM annual meeting</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/first/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/posts/first/</guid><description>Here we describe what you can expect from our DIC events from the OHBM 2021 annual meeting!
https://www.ohbmbrainmappingblog.com/blog/what-to-expect-from-the-diversity-and-inclusivity-committee-at-the-2021-ohbm-annual-meeting</description></item><item><title>Tzovara et al. Embracing diversity and inclusivity in an academic setting - Insights from the Organization for Human Brain Mapping</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/tzovara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/tzovara/</guid><description>Athina Tzovara, Ishmael Amarreh, Valentina Borghesani, M. Mallar Chakravarty, Elizabeth DuPre, Christian Grefkes, Amelie Haugg, Lee Jollans, Hyang Woon Lee, Sharlene D. Newman, Rosanna K. Olsen, J. Tilak Ratnanather, Gina Rippon, Lucina Q. Uddin, Maria L. Bringas Vega, Michele Veldsman, Tonya White, AmanPreet Badhwar, &amp;ldquo;Embracing diversity and inclusivity in an academic setting: Insights from the Organization for Human Brain Mapping&amp;rdquo;, NeuroImage, Volume 229, 2021, 117742, ISSN 1053-8119, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2021.117742.</description></item><item><title>Questions</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/contactus/questions2dic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/contactus/questions2dic/</guid><description>If you have any questions about our activities/events/projects, or if you are interested in joining our team, please send email to ohbmdic@gmail.com.</description></item><item><title>Reporting</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/contactus/reporting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/contactus/reporting/</guid><description>If someone makes you or anyone else feel unsafe or unwelcome, please report it as soon as possible to the OHBM Executive Director Beth Slater: bslater@humanbrainmapping.orgOHBM Code of Conduct: You can find the OHBM Code of Conduct in: https://www.</description></item><item><title>Technical Support</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/contactus/tech_support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/contactus/tech_support/</guid><description>This website is currently maintained by Kangjoo Lee and Fernanda H. de Moraes. For any inquiries, please send email to: ohbmdic@gmail.</description></item></channel></rss>