<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow on OHBM DIC</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/</link><description>Recent content in Brain Mappers of Tomorrow on OHBM DIC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Organization for Human Brain Mapping - Diversity and Inclusivity Committee. All rights reserved. | Contact OHBM-DIC</copyright><atom:link href="https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow: 2024</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/</guid><description>The Diversity and Inclusivity Committee (DIC) at OHBM organizes the annual Brain Mappers of Tomorrow (formerly Multilingual Kids Live Review) events in 2024 (FREE events).
In 2023, we hosted 17 1-hour sessions in 12 different languages to connect the scientists from today at OHBM to children (8-15 years old) all over the world. The main objective of these presentations is to have children learn about your scientific work and get them excited about science and the brain.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2021</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2021/</guid><description>Watch on youtube at https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLocwiMktiT-6qUcqfP1qronR16EHLW3NM</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2022</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2022/</guid><description>Watch on youtube at https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLocwiMktiT-5w99sH6XGSWwsMyj2TMlm_</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/</guid><description>The Diversity and Inclusivity Committee (DIC) at OHBM organizes the annual Multilingual Kids Live Review events in 2023 (FREE events). This year, we host 18 1-hour sessions in 12 different languages to connect the scientists from today at OHBM to children (8-15 years old) all over the world. The main objective of these presentations is to have children learn about your scientific work and get them excited about science and the brain.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Japanese 2024 - 知りたい？脳の中の高速道路</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/japanese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/japanese/</guid><description>赤ちゃんの脳はどのように育つの？ 国際ヒト脳マッピング学会 (Organization for Human Brain Mapping; OHBM)　ダイバーシティ・インクルーシビティ委員会では、未来の社会を担う子供達に脳の研究について知ってもらうためのイベントを世界各国の言語を用いて開催しています。 このイベントでは、１１歳から１８歳ぐらいの子供たちを対象に、脳（のう）の研究についての紹介を研究者が日本語で行います。今年のイベントでは、脳の研究の紹介を皆川　泰代（みながわ　やすよ）先生が行います。皆さんは、赤ちゃんの言葉や運動などの能力が育っているとき、脳はどのように変化しているのか興味を持ったことがありますか？今回、赤ちゃんの脳の不思議を皆さんにご紹介します！皆川先生からのお話の後に、皆さんからの質問コーナーも用意しています。赤ちゃんの脳のはたらきや、脳について知りたいな、と思っていることについて、一緒にお話しましょう！ なお、今年はオンサイトでの開催を予定しており、リモートでの視聴はできませんので、ご了承のほどお願いします。会場の都合上定員がありますので、定員に達し次第、受付を終了させていただきます。
日時: 2024年6月1日（土） 14:00〜15:00ごろ
場所: 開智日本橋学園中学・高等学校　地下１階セミナールーム （住所：東京都中央区日本橋馬喰町２−７−６）
参加定員: 35名
参加対象者: １１歳から１８歳で脳の研究に興味のある方および保護者や教育関係者の方
参加費: 無料
参加登録方法: 参加登録フォームの公開までお待ちください 参加申込締め切り: 2024年5月25日（土）。（ただし定員に達した場合は、予定より早く参加登録を終了する可能性あり）
How do baby brains work? The Organization for Human Brain Mapping (OHBM) Diversity and Inclusivity Committee organizes events in languages from around the world to inform children, the future leaders of society, about brain research. At this event, researchers will give a presentation in Japanese on brain research for children aged around 11 to 18 years old.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Korean (한국어) 2024</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/korean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/korean/</guid><description>연결된 우리, 보호되어야 하는 우리: 디지털 시대에서의 건강한 뇌 발달을 위해 여러분은 항상 작은 스마트폰을 가지고 어디에서든 친구들과 이야기를 나누고 게임을 즐기며 재미있는 영상을 시청할 수 있어요. 클릭 몇 번만으로도 우리는 언제 어디서나 친구, 사회, 세계와 연결될 수 있죠. 그러나 스마트폰을 너무 많이 사용하면 우리 마음과 머릿속에서는 어떤 일이 일어날까요?
친구의 표정을 잘 읽는 것은 친구관계에서 아주 중요합니다. 하지만 스마트폰을 너무 많이 사용하면 또래 친구들보다 친구나 가족들의 얼굴표정에서 감정의 변화를 잘 알아차리기 어려울 수도 있어요.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: Italian 2024 - Cos’è la memoria? E come la usiamo per imparare una nuova lingua</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/italian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/italian/</guid><description>Ciao!
Ci chiamiamo Irene e Isotta e siamo due neuroscienziate che studiano il funzionamento del cervello all’Università di Ginevra.
Isotta lavora sulla connettività cerebrale e sull&amp;rsquo;epilessia, una malattia caratterizzata da un&amp;rsquo;attivazione inaspettata in tutto il cervello (crisi epilettica). Pur lavorando per l&amp;rsquo;Università, la sua sede è l&amp;rsquo;ospedale, dove studia l&amp;rsquo;attività cerebrale dei pazienti per capire se è possibile trovare segni della malattia anche quando il cervello funziona in modo normale. Le crisi epilettiche spesso iniziano nell&amp;rsquo;ippocampo, una parte del cervello fondamentale per la memoria.</description></item></channel></rss>