<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow on OHBM DIC</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/</link><description>Recent content in Brain Mappers of Tomorrow on OHBM DIC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Organization for Human Brain Mapping - Diversity and Inclusivity Committee. All rights reserved. | Contact OHBM-DIC</copyright><atom:link href="https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow: 2025</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/</guid><description>The Diversity and Inclusivity Committee (DIC) at OHBM organizes the annual Brain Mappers of Tomorrow (formerly Multilingual Kids Live Review) events in 2025 (FREE events).
In 2023, we hosted 17 1-hour sessions in 12 different languages to connect the scientists from today at OHBM to children (8-15 years old) all over the world. The main objective of these presentations is to have children learn about your scientific work and get them excited about science and the brain.</description></item><item><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow: 2024</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2024/</guid><description>The Diversity and Inclusivity Committee (DIC) at OHBM organizes the annual Brain Mappers of Tomorrow (formerly Multilingual Kids Live Review) events in 2024 (FREE events).
In 2023, we hosted 17 1-hour sessions in 12 different languages to connect the scientists from today at OHBM to children (8-15 years old) all over the world. The main objective of these presentations is to have children learn about your scientific work and get them excited about science and the brain.</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2021</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2021/</guid><description>Watch on youtube at https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLocwiMktiT-6qUcqfP1qronR16EHLW3NM</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2022</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2022/</guid><description>Watch on youtube at https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLocwiMktiT-5w99sH6XGSWwsMyj2TMlm_</description></item><item><title>Kids Review: 2023</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2023/</guid><description>The Diversity and Inclusivity Committee (DIC) at OHBM organizes the annual Multilingual Kids Live Review events in 2023 (FREE events). This year, we host 18 1-hour sessions in 12 different languages to connect the scientists from today at OHBM to children (8-15 years old) all over the world. The main objective of these presentations is to have children learn about your scientific work and get them excited about science and the brain.</description></item><item><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow: English 2025 - A Road Trip down Memory Lane: Making Maps of the Brain’s Pathways with Diffusion MRI</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/english_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/english_session/</guid><description>A Road Trip down Memory Lane: Making Maps of the Brain’s Pathways with Diffusion MRI
How can we create images of the pathways connecting different areas of the brain without touching it? Diffusion magnetic resonance imaging makes this possible! In this presentation we explain how this technology works and share beautiful images of the brain.
Presenters and organizers -- Tanja Schmidt, Presenter. Tatjana Schmidt is a PhD candidate in Clinical Neurosciences at the University of Cambridge and a Gates Cambridge Scholar.</description></item><item><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow: Italian 2025 - Cos’è la memoria? E come la usiamo per imparare una nuova lingua</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/italian_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/italian_session/</guid><description>Ciao!
Ci chiamiamo Irene e Isotta e siamo due neuroscienziate che studiano il funzionamento del cervello all’Università di Ginevra.
Isotta lavora sulla connettività cerebrale e sull&amp;rsquo;epilessia, una malattia caratterizzata da un&amp;rsquo;attivazione inaspettata in tutto il cervello (crisi epilettica). Pur lavorando per l&amp;rsquo;Università, la sua sede è l&amp;rsquo;ospedale, dove studia l&amp;rsquo;attività cerebrale dei pazienti per capire se è possibile trovare segni della malattia anche quando il cervello funziona in modo normale. Le crisi epilettiche spesso iniziano nell&amp;rsquo;ippocampo, una parte del cervello fondamentale per la memoria.</description></item><item><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow: Mandarin 2025 - 大腦語語工作坊</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/mandarin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/mandarin/</guid><description>大腦語語工作坊 在這個工作坊，我們將透過介紹、討論，以及實作活動來一起探索大腦和語言的關係。我們會一起認識大腦的結構、語言與認知，以及大腦是如何分辨不同語言的。
The Brain Talks Seminar In this event, we will explore the relationship between the brain and language through an introductory presentation, group discussions as well as several hands-on activities. We will get to know the brain anatomy, brain and cognition, and how the brain recognizes a sound from a native language and another sound from a foreign language.
Presenters and organizers Tzuyi Tseng is a post doctoral researcher at the Laboratoire Dynamique Du Langage, Université Lumière Lyon 2.</description></item><item><title>Brain Mappers of Tomorrow: Portuguese 2025</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/portuguese_session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/kidsreview/2025/portuguese_session/</guid><description>De Mais Perto: Explorar os Caminhos Internos do Cérebro Esta apresentação mostra como técnicas avançadas de ressonância magnética, como a imagiologia microestrutural, permitem-nos observar o cérebro para além do que os exames tradicionais conseguem mostrar. Ao revelar estruturas microscópicas como os axónios — as “estradas” internas do cérebro — os investigadores obtêm novas pistas sobre o seu funcionamento, a sua comunicação e as alterações associadas a doenças.
Zooming In: Exploring the Brain’s Inner Pathways This presentation explores how advanced MRI techniques, such as microstructure imaging, allow us to see deeper into the brain than traditional scans.</description></item></channel></rss>