<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Links on OHBM DIC</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/</link><description>Recent content in Links on OHBM DIC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Organization for Human Brain Mapping - Diversity and Inclusivity Committee. All rights reserved. | Contact OHBM-DIC</copyright><atom:link href="https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Affinity Groups</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/affinitygroups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/affinitygroups/</guid><description>How can we achieve a balance of speakers at a scientific event? Finding speakers outside one’s network can be accomplished by contacting affinity groups that are organized around specific identities to seek eligible individuals with the relevant expertise on a given topic. This will entail including speakers from underrepresented backgrounds and geographical locations as well as considering gender, ethnicity, and career levels when choosing co-presenters.
We compiled a list of affinity groups https://docs.</description></item><item><title>References</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/references/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/references/</guid><description>Arenas-Castro, H., Berdejo-Espinola, V., Chowdhury, S., Rodríguez-Contreras, A., James, A. R., Raja, N. B., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Amano, T. (2024). Academic publishing requires linguistically inclusive policies. Proceedings of the Royal Society B, 291(2018), 20232840. http://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2023.2840 Liu, F., Rahwan, T., &amp;amp; AlShebli, B. (2023). Non-White scientists appear on fewer editorial boards, spend more time under review, and receive fewer citations. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 120(13), e2215324120.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/links/resources/</guid><description> Resources for Women in Academia https://sobp.org/women-in-academia-and-covid-19/ An annotated introductory reading list for neurodiversity: Zaneva, M., Coll-Martín, T., Héjja-Brichard, Y., Kalandadze, T., Kis, A., Koperska, A., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Zisk, A. H. (2024). An annotated introductory reading list for neurodiversity. Elife, 13, e102467. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.102467</description></item></channel></rss>