<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on OHBM DIC</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on OHBM DIC</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Organization for Human Brain Mapping - Diversity and Inclusivity Committee. All rights reserved. | Contact OHBM-DIC</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kam et al. Creating Diverse and Inclusive Scientific Practices for Research Datasets and Dissemination</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/kam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/kam/</guid><description>Julia W. Y. Kam, AmanPreet Badhwar, Valentina Borghesani, Kangjoo Lee, Stephanie Noble, Pradeep Reddy Raamana, Tilak Ratnanather, Davynn G.H. Tan, Hyang Woon Lee, Laura Marzetti, Hajer Nakua, Gina Rippon, Rosanna Olsen, Lucina Q. Uddin, Julio Alejandro Yanes, Athina Tzovara. “Creating Diverse and Inclusive Scientific Practices for Research Datasets and Dissemination.” PsyArXiv. 2024. https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/dr5hg.</description></item><item><title>Tzovara et al. Embracing diversity and inclusivity in an academic setting - Insights from the Organization for Human Brain Mapping</title><link>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/tzovara/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ohbm-dic.github.io/publications/tzovara/</guid><description>Athina Tzovara, Ishmael Amarreh, Valentina Borghesani, M. Mallar Chakravarty, Elizabeth DuPre, Christian Grefkes, Amelie Haugg, Lee Jollans, Hyang Woon Lee, Sharlene D. Newman, Rosanna K. Olsen, J. Tilak Ratnanather, Gina Rippon, Lucina Q. Uddin, Maria L. Bringas Vega, Michele Veldsman, Tonya White, AmanPreet Badhwar, &amp;ldquo;Embracing diversity and inclusivity in an academic setting: Insights from the Organization for Human Brain Mapping&amp;rdquo;, NeuroImage, Volume 229, 2021, 117742, ISSN 1053-8119, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2021.117742.</description></item></channel></rss>